To create a mail merge in Word for
Mac, there are some slight differences
than doing this in Word for Windows.
As you can see, all of the tabs are
the same, and there's the mailing
tab is there, which I can click
on, which will bring up the tools
required to create the mail merge.
I also have on the screen the letter
that I downloaded from the vision2learn
website to demonstrate with.
The first thing you need to do
when you're using Word for Mac to
create a mail merge is you have to
do each of the steps individually.
There's no mail merge wizard.
There's no facility to insert
address block and greeting line.
Each field has to be entered individually.
So the first thing to do is if I
click on start mail merge, you would
select the type of document that you
want to create the mail merge with.
So for this instance, it's a letter.
So quite happy with that.
So select letter.
I then need to select the recipients.
So selecting the recipient is basically
linking the letter with a data source
and the names and addresses of the people
who I'm sending the letter to have been
inserted into an Excel spreadsheet.
So if I click on that and I'm going
to use an existing list, so I then
need to navigate to where I have
saved the list of names and addresses.
And, I know it is in simple mail merge
addresses, so I could click open.
And again, this file I downloaded
from the vision2learn website.
I will get a message up asking me
if I'm sure I want to open this as
it may pose a security risk, but I
am secure in the knowledge that this
document is not corrupt in any way.
I select Yes.
And then it will open up a new dialog
box asking which sheet I want to take
the data from and I know it's sheet one.
And select OK.
So nothing's actually happened,
but it has linked the letter to
the mail merge address fields.
I now need to start
adding the merge fields.
So if I click on the insert merge
field button, I need to insert
the first name and then enter a
space and then the surname and then
press enter then address line one.
Enter.
Address line two.
Town.
Enter.
The County.
And the post code.
So that has now entered all of
the individual fields required
for the name and address.
I also wish to add a greeting
line, so I will press enter twice
to take me two lines down and
I will type in the word "dear".
And then press the space bar and go back
to the insert merge fields and select
first name and again, press the space bar.
And then surname.
So now that has inserted
the greeting lane.
I'm just going to back space just to
bring the letter, or the body of the
letter, up to beneath the greeting line.
I will have a quick look
and I'm happy with that.
I can then preview the
results of the merge.
So at the moment, it's just
showing the merge fields.
So if I click on preview results, it
will automatically link the data source
with the letter, so it will start
pulling through the names and addresses.
So as you can see, the first name and
address has come up there, William
Brown, and the greeting line, William
Brown, and I can then navigate across
to the preview for the next record.
And it will show me Jennifer
Green has been entered.
Fred White.
And Julie Black.
So at this point, I can do any,
make any changes or do something
different, or I can actually remove a
recipient or edit the recipients, so
you can filter the  recipients there.
I'm happy with that.
I would then go to the finish and
merge, click on that, and I can add that
edit individual documents so I could
make changes to a specific document.
Maybe that I'm offering a
better offer to one person than
another or print documents.
And if I click on print documents, I can
then decide which way I want to print it.
How many copies I want?
And so on.